A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Administration, Program and Policy, RG 3 FA112
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, administration, program and policy, RG 3
1910-2000
Rockefeller Archive Center
General Education Board. (New York, N.Y.)
Rockefeller Foundation
Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
FA112
194 Cubic Feet
Biographical / Historical
The Rockefeller Foundation was established by act of the New York State Legislature approved by the Governor on May 14, 1913, "to promote the well-being of mankind throughout the world." Between 1913 and 1928 the China Medical Board, the International Health Board, and the Division of Medical Education functioned as divisions of the Foundation, concentrating on the administration of programs in public health and medical education. A Division of Studies was created in 1923 to handle projects outside the medical field. These early years were experimental as the new foundation studied the methods of philanthropy and explored its relationships with other Rockefeller boards.
Although the Rockefeller Foundation is the largest and best known philanthropy founded by the Rockefeller family, it was neither the first nor the last to be established. The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (1901), the General Education Board (1902), the Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease (1909), and the Bureau of Social Hygiene (1911) all existed earlier. When the Foundation was created, the Sanitary Commission was disbanded. After the establishment of the Foundation, the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (1918) and the International Education Board (1923) were created.
The Rockefeller boards and their programs were reconsidered and reorganized in 1927-1928 in order to avoid overlapping programs. The International Health Board of the Foundation was disbanded and an International Health Division was organized. The China Medical Board, Inc., was established as a separately incorporated institution, and the China Medical Board of the Foundation ceased to exist. The Division of Studies was dropped and the Division of Medical Education was phased out. The Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial was combined with the Foundation and the Spelman Fund of New York was chartered to continue activities of the LSRM that were not absorbed by the Foundation. The International Education Board was disbanded.
As a result of this reorganization, the Foundation adopted a program which included public health work (administered by the IHD), the advancement of knowledge in the medical and natural sciences (in part taken over from the IEB), the social sciences (formerly the field of the LSRM), and the humanities and arts (shared with the GEB). The Rockefeller Institute and the Bureau of Social Hygiene were not affected by the reorganization. The program adopted by the Foundation at this time remained basically the same for the next twenty years.
As its files accumulated, the Foundation maintained a card index recording the names of institutional and individual grantees and correspondents. A microfilm copy of this index is available at the Archive Center.
Arrangement
The Administration, Program & Policy material is physically divided into two groups; RG 3.1 and RG 3.2. The first group contains earlier material, up to about 1950, while the second group contains mostly later material, roughly 1950 to 1980, though there are some exceptions.
There are 28 separate entries, arbitrarily numbered, dividing the material into areas of administrative or program interest. Files within these series are arranged alphabetically.
Many files in RG 3.1 continue into RG 3.2.
Conditions Governing Access
Material more than twenty years old is open for scholarly research.
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Scope and Contents
This material consists of administrative and program and policy information in the form of correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and reports.
The Foundation's archives include:
Projects General Correspondence Administration, Program and Policy China Medical Board International Health Board/Division Field Offices Treasurer's Office Comptroller Personnel Fellowships Information Services Diaries Oral Histories Counsel Secretary Minutes and Officers Actions Dockets Declinations (100F) Non-textual Materials Communications Office
Public health; Philanthropy; Medical sciences; Life sciences; Philanthropy -- United States; Humanities; Charities; Arts; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; General Education Board. (New York, N.Y.); Rockefeller Foundation; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
- Administration, Program and Policy, 1
  - General Program and Policy, 1910-1971; 900; 31 document cases
    Scope and Contents note
    Correspondence and reports related to administrative, financial, organizational, and program and policy matters. In the Program and Policy section of this series can be found general policy information and policy statements on specific questions which are not confined to one program. Of special interest is a 21 volume history of the Rockefeller Foundation compiled from original sources covering the years 1909-1939.
    - Agreements, 1924-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Agreements, 1924-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Commutation, 1918-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Commutation, 1918-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Commutation, 1918-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Commutation, 1918-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Commutation, 1918-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Decorations, 1916-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7.01)
    - Decorations, 1916-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7.02)
    - Decorations, 1916-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7.03)
    - Decorations, 1916-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7.04)
    - Decorations, 1916-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7.05)
    - Decorations, 1916-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7.06)
    - Decorations, 1916-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7.07)
    - Decorations, 1916-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7.08)
    - Decorations A, 1952-1967 (Box 001A, Folder 7.09)
    - Decorations B, 1929-1969 (Box 001A, Folder 7.1)
    - Decorations - Borlaug, Norman, 1968-1971 (Box 001A, Folder 7.11)
    - Decorations - Borlaug, Norman, 1968-1971 (Box 001A, Folder 7.12)
    - Decorations - Borlaug, Norman, 1968-1971 (Box 001A, Folder 7.13)
    - Decorations - Borlaug, Norman, 1968-1971 (Box 001A, Folder 7.14)
    - Decorations - Borlaug, Norman, 1968-1971 (Box 001A, Folder 7.15)
    - Decorations - Borlaug, Norman - Clippings, 1970-1971 (Box 001A, Folder 7.16)
    - Decorations - Borlaug, Norman - Nobel Lecture, 1970 (Box 001A, Folder 7.17)
    - Decorations - Bugher, John C., 1943-1967 (Box 001A, Folder 7.18)
    - Decorations C, 1930-1968 (Box 001A, Folder 7.19)
    - Decorations D, 1933-1969 (Box 001A, Folder 7.2)
    - Decorations E, 1946-1954 (Box 001A, Folder 7.21)
    - Decorations F, 1938-1964 (Box 001A, Folder 7.22)
    - Decorations G, 1923-1963 (Box 001A, Folder 7.23)
    - Decorations - Grant, John B., 1937-1961 (Box 001A, Folder 7.24)
    - Decorations - Gregg, Alan, 1927-1969 (Box 001A, Folder 7.25)
    - Decorations H, 1929-1962 (Box 001A, Folder 7.26)
    - Decorations - Hydrick, John L., 1928-1960 (Box 001B, Folder 7.27)
    - Decorations - Harrar, J. George, 1950-1971 (Box 001B, Folder 7.28)
    - Decorations - Harrar, J. George, 1950-1971 (Box 001B, Folder 7.29)
    - Decorations - Harrar, J. George, 1950-1971 (Box 001B, Folder 7.3)
    - Decorations I, 1967 (Box 001B, Folder 7.31)
    - Decorations J, 1945-1967 (Box 001B, Folder 7.32)
    - Decorations K, 1933-1959 (Box 001B, Folder 7.33)
    - Decorations L, 1935-1937 (Box 001B, Folder 7.34)
    - Decorations M, 1934-1958 (Box 001B, Folder 7.35)
    - Decorations - Miller, H. M., 1945-1966 (Box 001B, Folder 7.36)
    - Decorations - Miller, H. M., 1945-1966 (Box 001B, Folder 7.37)
    - Decorations - Miller, H. M., 1945-1966 (Box 001B, Folder 7.38)
    - Decorations N, 1920-1968 (Box 001B, Folder 7.39)
    - Decorations O, 1949 (Box 001B, Folder 7.4)
    - Decorations P, 1930-1952 (Box 001B, Folder 7.41)
    - Decorations R, 1927-1962 (Box 001B, Folder 7.42)
    - Decorations - Roberts, Lewis M., 1953-1963 (Box 001B, Folder 7.43)
    - Decorations - Russell, Paul, 1945-1963 (Box 001B, Folder 7.44)
    - Decorations - Russell, Frederick F., 1925-1937 (Box 001B, Folder 7.45)
    - Decorations S, 1938-1969 (Box 001B, Folder 7.46)
    - Decorations - Soper, Fred L., 1933-1962 (Box 001B, Folder 7.47)
    - Decorations - Strode, George K., 1929-1950 (Box 001B, Folder 7.48)
    - Decorations - Stakman, Elvin C., 1956-1964 (Box 001B, Folder 7.49)
    - Decorations T, 1939-1964 (Box 001B, Folder 7.5)
    - Decorations V, 1922-1930 (Box 001B, Folder 7.51)
    - Decorations W, 1926-1965 (Box 001C, Folder 7.52)
    - Decorations - Weaver, Warren, 1948-1957 (Box 001C, Folder 7.53)
    - Decorations - Weir, John, 1949-1969 (Box 001C, Folder 7.54)
    - Decorations - Wellhausen, E. J., 1957-1969 (Box 001C, Folder 7.55)
    - Decorations - Rockefeller (Use of Name), 1922-1946 (Box 001C, Folder 7.56)
    - Decorations - Rockefeller (Use of Name), 1922-1946 (Box 001C, Folder 7.57)
    - Decorations - Rockefeller (Use of Name), 1922-1946 (Box 001C, Folder 7.58)
    - Decorations - Rockefeller Family, 1912-1962 (Box 001C, Folder 7.59)
    - Decorations - Rockefeller Family, 1912-1962 (Box 001C, Folder 7.6)
    - Decorations - Rockefeller Family, 1912-1962 (Box 001C, Folder 7.61)
    - Decorations - Rockefeller Family, 1912-1962 (Box 001C, Folder 7.62)
    - Documents of Record, 1930-1939 (Box 001C, Folder 8)
    - Documents of Record - Reports (Box 001C, Folder 9)
      DR CMB-1: China Medical Board, Document of Record; 1914-1927
      DR SD-1: International Health Commission, Board and Division Documents of Record; June 27, 1913 to date [1927]
    - Entertainment, 1921-1965 (Box 001C, Folder 10)
    - Entertainment, 1921-1965 (Box 001C, Folder 11)
    - Financial Administration, 1922-1951 (Box 001C, Folder 12)
    - Financial Administration, 1922-1951 (Box 001C, Folder 13)
    - Financial Administration, 1910-1915 (Box 001C, Folder 14)
    - Financial Administration, 1916-1951 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Financial Administration, 1916-1951 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Financial Administration, 1916-1951 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Financial Administration, 1916-1951 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Financial Administration, 1916-1951 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Financial Administration, 1916-1951 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Financial Administration - Reports - Fin-1 - Fin-4 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Fin-1: Report of Committee on RF Accounting Procedure; February 23, 1921
      Fin-2: Implications of the Merger with the (Laura Spelman Rockefeller) Memorial and the Effect Upon the... ..; November 9, 1928
      Fin-3: Statement re: Method of Payment on Account of RF Pledges and Appropriations; November 18, 1929
      Fin-4 DR 416: Conspectus of Estimated Income and Estimated Expenditures Over a Ten-Year Period; 1930-1940
    - Financial Administration - Reports - Fin-5 DS-1, March 1934 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Fin-5 DS-1: List of Appropriations 1913-1933; March 1934
    - Financial Administration - Reports - Fin-5 - Fin-6, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      Fin-5: List of Appropriations 1913-1933 Appendix; March 1934
      Fin-6: Rockefeller Foundation and International Education Board; Expenditures by Geographic Areas, May 22, 1913 - December 31, 1933; 1934
    - Financial Administration - Reports - Fin-7a, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      Fin-7a: List of Grants by Field; April 1, 1927-December 31, 1934
    - Financial Administration - Reports - Fin-7b - Fin-8, 1928-1933 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Fin-7b: List of Grants by Country; April 1, 1927-December 31, 1933
      Fin-8: Expenditures During the Period; May 22, 1913-December 31, 1928
    - Financial Administration - Reports - Fin-9, Volume 1, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      Fin-9, Volume 1: Lapse of Unused Balances of Appropriations; January 1930-December 1934
    - Financial Administration - Reports - Fin-9, Volume 2, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Fin-9, Volume 2: Lapse of Unused Balances of Appropriations; January 1930-December 1934
    - Financial Administration - Reports - Fin-9, Volume 3, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Fin-9, Volume 3: Lapse of Unused Balances of Appropriations; 1951-1959
    - Financial Administration - Reports - Fin-10-Fin-14, 1934-1944 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      Fin-10: Financial Implications of Program Recommendations (Extract from the Report of the Committee on Appraisal and Planning. Complete report including all divisions filed 900 Pro-27); December 11, 1934
      Fin-11: Thomas B. Appleget; Financial Forecast of Income and Appropriations; July 11, 1935
      Fin-12: Thomas B. Appleget; Funds Available, Appropriations, Pledges, and Authorizations; July 22, 1936
      Fin-13: The Financial Policy of the RF-Trustees Meeting; December 6, 1939
      Fin-14: Appropriations for Endowment Purposes I. May 27-December31, 1938, II. 1939-1941, III. 1935-1944; Flat Grants Available Over a Period of Years Paid Outright; Grants for Endowment 1914-1944; Terminal Appropriations Paid in Full at Time Grants Were Made; Options for Payment of Endowment Appropriations; 1944
    - Financial Administration - Reports - Fin-15, Vols. I & II, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      Fin-15, Volume I DR 581, DR 602, DR 624, DR 644, DR 659, DR 690, DR 712: Summary of appropriations- 1913 to date; Financial Position, Record of Income presented annually at the December Meeting of the Trustees; 1941-1963
      Fin-15, Volume II: Summary of appropriations- 1913 to date; Financial Position, Record of Income presented annually at the December Meeting of the Trustees; 1964
    - Financial Administration - Reports - Fin-17, Fin-19-Fin-21a, 1943-1946 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      Fin-17: Expenditures by Geographical Areas Excluding the United States; 1943
      Fin-19: Norma S. Thompson; List of Precedents for Grants and Proposals for Underwriting Funds, Loans, Tapering and Matching Funds; October 24, 1946
      Fin-20: Norma S. Thompson; Statement of Policy re: Appropriations from Principal Funds; 1914-1946
      Fin-21: Resolution re: Budgetary Control of Appropriations with Appendices VII-XII; Section IX and Appendices VII-XI part of DR 677 excerpt from Report of Special Committee on Program and Policy; December 3-4, 1946
      Fin-21a: Report of the Special Committee on Policy and Program of the Rockefeller Foundation; Section IX Budgetary Control of Appropriations (original form); December 1946
    - Financial Administration - Reports - Fin-18, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 0031a)
      Fin-18: Budget System (1925); Compilation of Minutes of Budget Committee; 1925-1927
    - Financial Administration - Auditors, 1928-1941 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Financial Administration - Auditors, 1942-1949 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Financial Administration - Bank Accounts, 1933-1941 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Financial Administration - Bank Accounts, 1942-1949 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Financial Administration - Endowment, 1910-1941 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Financial Administration - Endowment, 1942-1970 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Financial Administration - Exchange, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Financial Administration - Exchange, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Financial Administration - Exchange, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Financial Administration - Exchange, 1942-1966, 1973, 1977, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Financial Administration - Founder's Designations, 1913-1960 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Financial Administration - Founder's Designations, 1913-1960 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Financial Administration - Gifts, 1917-1939 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Financial Administration - Gifts, 1943-1966 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Financial Administration - Gifts - Havas, 1943-1947 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Financial Administration - Gifts - Hendry, 1938-1946 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Financial Administration - Gifts - Phelps, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Financial Administration - Gifts - White, 1923-1927 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Financial Administration - Gifts - A-Z, 1929-1948 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Financial Administration - Gifts - A-Z, 1929-1948 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Financial Administration - Taxation, 1918-1941 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Financial Administration - Taxation, 1942-1950 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Financial Administration - Taxation, 1942-1950 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Financial Administration - Taxation - Personnel, 1916-1949 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Financial Administration - Taxation - Personnel, 1916-1949 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Financial Administration - Treasurer, 1916-1960 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Financial Administration - Treasurer, 1916-1960 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Financial Administration - Gratuities, 1929-1948 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Financial Administration - Gratuities, 1929-1948 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - History, 1913-1966 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - History, 1913-1966 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - History, 1913-1966 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - History, 1913-1966 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - History, 1913-1966 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - History - Dixon, J. Curtis, 1967-1969 (Box 006A, Folder 65.01)
    - History - Grant, John B., 1959-1966 (Box 006A, Folder 65.02)
    - History - Grant, John B., 1959-1966 (Box 006A, Folder 65.03)
    - History - Grant, John B., 1959-1966 (Box 006A, Folder 65.04)
    - History - Grant, John B., 1959-1966 (Box 006A, Folder 65.05)
    - History - Grant, John B., 1959-1966 (Box 006A, Folder 65.06)
    - History - Grant, John B., 1959-1966 (Box 006A, Folder 65.07)
    - History - Gregg, Alan, 1958-1966 (Box 006A, Folder 65.08)
    - History - Rhind, Flora, 1967-1970 (Box 006A, Folder 65.09)
    - History - Watson, Robert Briggs, 1967-1969 (Box 006A, Folder 65.1)
    - History - Weaver, Warren, 1960-1965 (Box 006A, Folder 65.11)
    - History - Reports - Hist-3 - Hist-5, 1936-1952 (Box 7, Folder 66)
      Hist-3: History of Foundation Program (copy filed 900 Pro-29); 1913-1936
      Hist-4 DR 560: Remarks of the Retiring Chairman, Mr. John D. Rockefeller Foundation; April 3, 1940
      Hist-5: A Brief History of the Rockefeller Foundation (with addendum); May 1952
    - History - Reports - Hist-6, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 0066a)
      Hist-6: Raymond B. Fosdick; Letters of comment on "The Story of the Rockefeller Foundation;" 1952
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 1-3 (Box 7, Folder 67)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      The archival material has been reformatted. Access to the original archival material is restricted. User copies of the microfilm are available for scholarly access.
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 1-3 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 1-3 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 4-6 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 4-6 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 4-6 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 7-9 (Box 9, Folder 73)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 7-9 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 7-9 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 10-13 (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 10-13 (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 10-13 (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 10-13 (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 14-17 (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 14-17 (Box 11, Folder 81)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 14-17 (Box 11, Folder 82)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 14-17 (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 18-21 (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 18-21 (Box 12, Folder 85)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 18-21 (Box 12, Folder 86)
    - History-2 - Source material, Volumes 18-21 (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - History-2 - Projects, Volumes 1-3 (Box 13, Folder 88)
    - History-2 - Projects, Volumes 1-3 (Box 13, Folder 89)
    - History-2 - Projects, Volumes 1-3 (Box 13, Folder 90)
    - Interdivisional Cooperation - Joint Operations Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 91)
    - Office Space - RCA Building, 1933-1941 (Box 14, Folder 92)
    - Office Space - RCA Building, 1933-1941 (Box 14, Folder 93)
    - Office Space - RCA Building - Leases, 1933-1940 (Box 14, Folder 94)
    - Office Space - RCA Building, 1942-1960 (Box 14, Folder 95)
    - Office Space - RCA Building, 1942-1960 (Box 14, Folder 96)
    - Office Space - RCA Building Leases, 1946-1956 (Box 14, Folder 97)
    - Office Space - 61 Broadway, 1915-1930 (Box 14, Folder 98)
    - Office Space - 61 Broadway, 1931-1935 (Box 15, Folder 99)
    - Office Space - 61 Broadway Leases, 1929, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 100)
    - Office Space - Spring Street, 1936-1968 (Box 15, Folder 101)
    - Office Space - Spring Street, 1936-1968 (Box 15, Folder 102)
    - Office Space - Spring Street Leases, 1936-1969 (Box 15, Folder 103)
    - Office Space - White Street, 1920-1936 (Box 15, Folder 104)
    - Officers, 1916-1948 (Box 15, Folder 105)
    - Officers, 1916-1948 (Box 15, Folder 106)
    - Officers - Attendance at Meetings, 1930-1958 (Box 15, Folder 107)
    - Officers - Attendance at Meetings, 1930-1958 (Box 15, Folder 108)
    - Organization Minutes, 1919-1936 (Box 15, Folder 109)
    - Organization, 1910-April 1912 (Box 15, Folder 110)
    - Organization, 1910-April 1912 (Box 15, Folder 111)
    - Organization, 1910-April 1912 (Box 15, Folder 112)
    - Organization, 1910-April 1912 (Box 15, Folder 113)
    - Organization, May 1912-1913 (Box 16, Folder 114)
    - Organization, May 1912-1913 (Box 16, Folder 115)
    - Organization, May 1912-1913 (Box 16, Folder 116)
    - Organization, May 1912-1913 (Box 16, Folder 117)
    - Organization, May 1912-1913 (Box 16, Folder 118)
    - Organization, May 1912-1913 (Box 16, Folder 119)
    - Organization, 1914-1948 (Box 17, Folder 120)
    - Organization, 1914-1948 (Box 17, Folder 121)
    - Organization, 1914-1948 (Box 17, Folder 122)
    - Organization, 1914-1948 (Box 17, Folder 123)
    - Organization, 1914-1948 (Box 17, Folder 124)
    - Organization, 1914-1948 (Box 17, Folder 125)
    - Organization, 1914-1948 (Box 17, Folder 126)
    - Organization, 1914-1948 (Box 17, Folder 127)
    - Organization Reports - Org-1, 1910-1913 (Box 18, Folder 128)
      Org-1: Jerome D. Greene; The Proposed Incorporation of the Rockefeller Foundation In the District of Columbia; February 1, 1913
      Org-1: Mr. Peters; A Bill to Incorporate the Rockefeller Foundation, 62nd Congress, 2nd Session H.R. 19, 227; February 1912
      Org-1: Mr. Gallinger; Hearing before Committee on the District of Columbia; U.S. Senate Bill to Incorporate the Rockefeller Foundation. 62nd Congress, 1st Session- S.2675, S.6888, 62nd Congress, 2nd Session- H.R. 21, 532; 1910-1913
      Org-1: Brief Incorporation of the Rockefeller Foundation
    - Organization Reports - Org-2 - Org-6 DR 21, 1913-1914 (Box 18, Folder 129)
      Org-2: Waiver of Notice of First Meeting; May 22, 1913